<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving
and Interchange DTD v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1.dtd">
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" dtd-version="1.2" article-type="other">
  <front>
    <journal-meta>
      <journal-id/>
      <journal-title-group>
        <journal-title>NIH Grant Proposal</journal-title>
      </journal-title-group>
      <issn/>
      <publisher>
        <publisher-name/>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <title-group>
        <article-title>Comparing Patient-Reported Outcomes Between Dupilumab and
Conventional Therapy in Adults with Moderate-to-Severe Atopic
Dermatitis</article-title>
        <subtitle>HPO 677 Final Project - NIH Grant Proposal
(PAR-24-280)</subtitle>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes">
          <name>
            <surname>Neri</surname>
            <given-names>Louie</given-names>
          </name>
          <string-name>Louie Neri</string-name>
          <xref ref-type="corresp" rid="cor-1">*</xref>
        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
        <corresp id="cor-1"/>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date date-type="pub" publication-format="electronic" iso-8601-date="2026-04-16">
        <year>2026</year>
        <month>4</month>
        <day>16</day>
      </pub-date>
      <history/>
      <abstract>
        <p>This grant proposal compares patient-reported outcomes between
dupilumab and conventional therapy in adults with moderate-to-severe
atopic dermatitis using observational electronic health record data.</p>
      </abstract>
      <kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
        <kwd>Atopic dermatitis</kwd>
        <kwd>Dupilumab</kwd>
        <kwd>Patient-reported outcomes</kwd>
        <kwd>Comparative effectiveness</kwd>
        <kwd>Grant proposal</kwd>
      </kwd-group>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
  <body>
    <sec id="specific-aims">
      <title>1. Specific Aims</title>
      <p>Atopic dermatitis (AD) is a chronic inflammatory skin condition
  affecting an estimated 7% to 10% of adults in the United States
  (<xref alt="Silverberg and Hanifin 2013" rid="ref-silverberg_adult_2013" ref-type="bibr">Silverberg
  and Hanifin 2013</xref>). Moderate-to-severe AD produces persistent
  pruritus, sleep disturbance, visible skin changes, and psychological
  distress, which together reduce quality of life and elevate the risk
  of depression and anxiety
  (<xref alt="Silverberg et al. 2018" rid="ref-silverberg_patient_2018" ref-type="bibr">Silverberg
  et al. 2018</xref>). The disease burden experienced by patients
  extends well beyond what clinical severity scores capture.</p>
      <p>Dupilumab, a biologic therapy targeting IL-4 and IL-13 signaling,
  has reshaped the treatment landscape for moderate-to-severe AD since
  its FDA approval in 2017
  (<xref alt="Simpson et al. 2016" rid="ref-simpson_two_2016" ref-type="bibr">Simpson
  et al. 2016</xref>). The evidence supporting its use, however, comes
  largely from randomized controlled trials with restrictive eligibility
  criteria. These trials typically exclude older adults, patients with
  multiple comorbidities, and those on concurrent medications, which
  limits how well their findings translate to routine clinical practice.
  Real-world data comparing patient-reported outcomes (PROs) between
  dupilumab and conventional therapy remain sparse, particularly over
  the 12-month time horizon relevant to clinical decision-making
  (<xref alt="Afshari et al. 2024" rid="ref-afshari_unraveling_2024" ref-type="bibr">Afshari
  et al. 2024</xref>).</p>
      <p>This gap matters for three reasons. First, clinicians and patients
  making treatment decisions lack robust comparative data on outcomes
  that reflect what patients actually experience. Second, cost
  differences between biologic and conventional therapies are
  substantial. Out-of-pocket costs for dupilumab can reach several
  thousand dollars per year depending on insurance coverage, and the
  resulting financial burden can independently worsen depressive
  symptoms even when skin symptoms improve
  (<xref alt="Drucker et al. 2017" rid="ref-drucker_burden_2017" ref-type="bibr">Drucker
  et al. 2017</xref>). Third, understanding these trade-offs is
  essential for shared decision-making that reflects both clinical
  effectiveness and the patient-centered consequences of treatment
  choice.</p>
      <p>The long-term goal of this research is to generate real-world
  evidence on patient-centered outcomes that can inform treatment
  selection and health policy for adults with moderate-to-severe AD. The
  objective of this application is to compare changes in
  disease-specific quality of life and depressive symptoms between
  patients initiating dupilumab versus conventional therapy over 12
  months, using electronic health record (EHR) data from a large
  academic medical center. The underlying rationale is that
  observational data reflecting real-world clinical pathways complement
  trial evidence and identify outcomes meaningful to patients, which
  supports the design of future clinical studies. This proposal responds
  to PAR-24-280, Clinical Observational Studies in Musculoskeletal,
  Rheumatic, and Skin Diseases, which seeks well-designed observational
  research that improves understanding of disease symptoms and outcomes
  important to patients with skin conditions.</p>
      <p>The specific aims are:</p>
      <p><bold>Aim 1: Compare 12-month changes in disease-specific quality
  of life between dupilumab and conventional therapy.</bold> Changes in
  the Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI)
  (<xref alt="Finlay and Khan 1994" rid="ref-finlay_dermatology_1994" ref-type="bibr">Finlay
  and Khan 1994</xref>) will be evaluated between treatment groups, with
  confounding by indication addressed through inverse probability of
  treatment weighting (IPTW). The working hypothesis is that
  dupilumab-treated patients will show greater DLQI improvement than
  those on conventional therapy, with differences exceeding the minimal
  clinically important difference (MCID) of 4 points
  (<xref alt="Basra et al. 2015" rid="ref-basra_determining_2015" ref-type="bibr">Basra
  et al. 2015</xref>).</p>
      <p><bold>Aim 2: Compare 12-month changes in depressive symptoms
  between dupilumab and conventional therapy.</bold> Changes in the
  Patient Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9)
  (<xref alt="Kroenke, Spitzer, and Williams 2001" rid="ref-kroenke_phq-9_2001" ref-type="bibr">Kroenke,
  Spitzer, and Williams 2001</xref>) will be evaluated between treatment
  groups using the same IPTW approach. The hypothesis is that
  dupilumab-treated patients will show greater reductions in depressive
  symptoms, consistent with the established relationship between skin
  disease burden and psychological well-being.</p>
      <p><bold>Aim 3: Examine whether treatment effects vary by age, sex,
  and race.</bold> Prespecified interaction terms will test for effect
  modification by demographic characteristics. This aim will identify
  subgroups that may experience differential benefits and will surface
  potential disparities in treatment outcomes. Insurance status and
  socioeconomic factors will be examined as exploratory moderators.</p>
      <p>The expected output is real-world comparative effectiveness
  evidence on patient-reported outcomes in AD that is directly relevant
  to clinical decision-making. Secondary contributions include
  characterizing disease symptom trajectories under routine care,
  supporting the use of DLQI and PHQ-9 as endpoints in future clinical
  studies, and identifying sources of treatment effect heterogeneity
  that can inform efforts to reduce disparities in AD care. This work
  aligns with the NIAMS mission to improve outcomes and function in
  patients with skin conditions.</p>
      <p/>
    </sec>
    <sec id="research-strategy">
      <title>2. Research Strategy</title>
      <sec id="significance">
        <title>2.1 Significance</title>
        <sec id="burden-of-atopic-dermatitis">
          <title>2.1.1 Burden of atopic dermatitis</title>
          <p>AD is the most common chronic inflammatory skin disease and
      affects a substantial proportion of US adults
      (<xref alt="Silverberg and Hanifin 2013" rid="ref-silverberg_adult_2013" ref-type="bibr">Silverberg
      and Hanifin 2013</xref>). The condition is characterized by
      intense pruritus, erythematous and excoriated lesions, and a
      relapsing-remitting course that meaningfully diminishes quality of
      life. The associated sleep disturbance, social stigma, impaired
      work productivity, and elevated rates of depression and anxiety
      amplify this burden considerably
      (<xref alt="Yu et al. 2018" rid="ref-yu_systematic_2018" ref-type="bibr">Yu
      et al. 2018</xref>). The psychosocial impact of moderate-to-severe
      AD can be comparable to that of asthma and diabetes
      (<xref alt="Eckert et al. 2017" rid="ref-eckert_impact_2017" ref-type="bibr">Eckert
      et al. 2017</xref>), and the outcomes patients care about most are
      experiential: how the disease affects daily activities,
      relationships, and emotional well-being rather than the specific
      values on a clinical severity scale.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="treatment-options-and-the-limits-of-current-evidence">
          <title>2.1.2 Treatment options and the limits of current
      evidence</title>
          <p>Conventional therapy includes topical corticosteroids,
      calcineurin inhibitors, and systemic immunosuppressants such as
      cyclosporine, methotrexate, and mycophenolate mofetil. These
      agents can reduce disease severity but carry risks of long-term
      toxicity and yield variable efficacy
      (<xref alt="Eichenfield et al. 2014" rid="ref-eichenfield_guidelines_2014" ref-type="bibr">Eichenfield
      et al. 2014</xref>). Dupilumab, the first FDA-approved biologic
      for AD, has demonstrated efficacy in pivotal randomized trials
      (<xref alt="Simpson et al. 2016" rid="ref-simpson_two_2016" ref-type="bibr">Simpson
      et al. 2016</xref>). Those trials, however, enrolled highly
      selected populations under controlled conditions. Their findings
      do not necessarily extend to the broader population seen in
      routine practice, where adherence is lower, comorbidities are
      common, and clinical monitoring is less frequent.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="gaps-in-patient-reported-outcomes-evidence">
          <title>2.1.3 Gaps in patient-reported outcomes evidence</title>
          <p>Despite growing adoption of dupilumab, head-to-head
      observational comparisons of patient-reported outcomes between
      biologic and conventional therapy in real-world settings remain
      limited. Most existing studies rely on clinician-assessed severity
      scores such as EASI and SCORAD
      (<xref alt="Chopra and Silverberg 2018" rid="ref-chopra_assessing_2018" ref-type="bibr">Chopra
      and Silverberg 2018</xref>). Clinical severity captures important
      biological information but does not reflect the full scope of what
      patients experience. DLQI was chosen for this study because it is
      a condition-specific instrument that captures the particular
      impact of skin disease on daily life, and because
      condition-specific measures tend to be more responsive to
      treatment-related change than generic measures when a real
      treatment effect is present. PHQ-9 adds a complementary dimension
      by capturing depressive symptom burden, which is a recognized
      comorbidity that amplifies overall disease impact. The pairing of
      these two instruments produces a more complete picture of how
      treatments affect patients than either clinical severity scores or
      generic health measures alone.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="financial-toxicity-and-access-disparities">
          <title>2.1.4 Financial toxicity and access disparities</title>
          <p>Out-of-pocket costs for dupilumab vary widely depending on
      insurance coverage, ranging from minimal copayments to several
      thousand dollars annually
      (<xref alt="Drucker et al. 2017" rid="ref-drucker_burden_2017" ref-type="bibr">Drucker
      et al. 2017</xref>). This variation creates selection effects in
      who receives biologic therapy, with implications for both the
      internal validity of observational comparisons and for health
      equity. Financial burden can also independently worsen depression
      scores and reduce adherence, potentially attenuating treatment
      benefits regardless of pharmacologic efficacy. These cost-related
      dynamics must be accounted for when interpreting PRO differences
      between treatment groups and when designing future studies that
      address economic barriers to care.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="importance-to-the-field">
          <title>2.1.5 Importance to the field</title>
          <p>By generating the kind of observational evidence that
      PAR-24-280 is designed to support, this project will provide data
      that directly inform the design of future clinical studies in AD,
      including identification of appropriate primary endpoints and
      characterization of the subgroups most likely to benefit from
      biologic therapy.</p>
        </sec>
      </sec>
      <sec id="innovation">
        <title>2.2 Innovation</title>
        <p>This proposal advances the field in five respects.</p>
        <p><italic>Dual patient-reported outcome focus.</italic> Existing
    comparative studies of AD treatments have predominantly relied on
    clinician-assessed severity endpoints
    (<xref alt="Chopra and Silverberg 2018" rid="ref-chopra_assessing_2018" ref-type="bibr">Chopra
    and Silverberg 2018</xref>). Centering this study on two validated
    patient-reported instruments as co-primary outcomes shifts the
    evidentiary focus toward what patients experience. DLQI captures
    disease-specific impact on daily life and has strong responsiveness
    in dermatology populations; PHQ-9 captures psychological burden and
    is widely established for depression screening and severity
    assessment. Pairing a condition-specific instrument with a mental
    health instrument is uncommon in comparative AD research and
    reflects the multidimensional nature of disease impact.</p>
        <p><italic>Integration of mental health outcomes in dermatology
    research.</italic> Depression is a recognized comorbidity of AD
    (<xref alt="Yu et al. 2018" rid="ref-yu_systematic_2018" ref-type="bibr">Yu
    et al. 2018</xref>), but few observational studies have
    systematically tracked depressive symptom trajectories across
    treatment strategies. Including PHQ-9 as a primary endpoint
    alongside DLQI makes the psychological dimension of treatment
    benefit testable rather than assumed.</p>
        <p><italic>Systematic evaluation of treatment effect
    heterogeneity.</italic> A single average treatment effect can mask
    substantial variation across subgroups. This study formally tests
    whether benefits differ by age, sex, and race. Given documented
    disparities in AD treatment access across demographic groups
    (<xref alt="Tackett et al. 2020" rid="ref-tackett_structural_2020" ref-type="bibr">Tackett
    et al. 2020</xref>), this approach identifies subgroups that may
    experience differential benefits. Effect modification will be
    assessed through formal interaction tests rather than side-by-side
    comparison of significance labels across strata, the latter being a
    common but invalid way to establish that effects truly differ.</p>
        <p><italic>Methodological rigor in addressing confounding by
    indication.</italic> Patients receiving dupilumab typically have
    more severe, refractory disease than those on conventional therapy.
    IPTW will create a pseudo-population in which measured baseline
    covariates are balanced across treatment groups, and covariate
    balance will be verified through standardized mean differences
    (threshold: SMD &lt; 0.1) and propensity score overlap to evaluate
    positivity. E-value sensitivity analyses will quantify how strong an
    unmeasured confounder would need to be to explain away observed
    effects
    (<xref alt="VanderWeele and Ding 2017" rid="ref-vanderweele_sensitivity_2017" ref-type="bibr">VanderWeele
    and Ding 2017</xref>). The combination provides a transparent
    framework for causal interpretation in an observational setting.</p>
        <p><italic>Emphasis on clinical meaningfulness.</italic>
    Interpretation will center on effect size, confidence interval
    width, and compatibility with established MCIDs (DLQI: 4 points,
    (<xref alt="Basra et al. 2015" rid="ref-basra_determining_2015" ref-type="bibr">Basra
    et al. 2015</xref>); PHQ-9: 5 points,
    (<xref alt="Kroenke, Spitzer, and Williams 2001" rid="ref-kroenke_phq-9_2001" ref-type="bibr">Kroenke,
    Spitzer, and Williams 2001</xref>)), rather than on whether a result
    crosses a p-value threshold. Statistically significant findings do
    not guarantee clinically important effects, particularly in large
    samples where small differences can produce low p-values.
    Nonsignificant findings in smaller samples may reflect imprecision
    rather than absence of effect. Interpretation grounded in effect
    magnitude and clinical thresholds is more useful for treatment
    decisions than a binary significance label.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="approach">
        <title>2.3 Approach</title>
        <sec id="overview-and-conceptual-model">
          <title>2.3.1 Overview and conceptual model</title>
          <p>This prospective cohort study will compare patient-reported
      outcomes between adults with moderate-to-severe AD initiating
      dupilumab versus conventional therapy. The conceptual model serves
      as the organizing framework: treatment type (the primary exposure)
      affects disease activity, itch intensity, and sleep disturbance,
      which in turn influence DLQI and PHQ-9. Confounders including
      baseline disease severity, treatment history, insurance status,
      comorbidities, and socioeconomic factors affect both treatment
      selection and outcomes and must be addressed through propensity
      score methods. The model assigns each variable an explicit role as
      exposure, mediator, moderator, or confounder, which prevents the
      analysis from devolving into a list of variables without rationale
      and ensures every analytic decision ties back to the hypothesized
      causal structure.</p>
          <fig id="fig-conceptual-model">
            <caption>
              <p>Figure 1: Conceptual model. The primary causal
        pathway runs from treatment through mediators to outcomes.
        Confounders influence both treatment selection and outcomes,
        creating the need for propensity score adjustment.</p>
            </caption>
            <graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="png" xlink:href="index_files/figure-jats/fig-conceptual-model-1.png"/>
          </fig>
        </sec>
        <sec id="study-design">
          <title>2.3.2 Study design</title>
          <p>A prospective cohort design is appropriate because randomizing
      patients to dupilumab versus conventional therapy is neither
      practical nor ethical. Dupilumab is typically prescribed after
      conventional options have failed, and insurance authorization
      creates natural treatment pathways that a research protocol cannot
      easily override. Two cohorts will be enrolled at treatment
      initiation and followed for 12 months, with PROs collected at
      baseline and at 3, 6, and 12 months. Prospective collection
      ensures standardized outcome measurement rather than reliance on
      inconsistently documented chart data.</p>
          <p>The principal threat to validity is confounding by indication.
      Dupilumab recipients tend to have more severe disease, meaning
      baseline differences between groups could bias observed
      associations. This is a structural problem that propensity score
      methods partially address for measured confounders but cannot
      address for unmeasured ones, which is why sensitivity analyses are
      essential.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="study-population-and-data-source">
          <title>2.3.3 Study population and data source</title>
          <p>EHR data from a large academic medical center with an active
      dermatology specialty clinic will be used. EHR data add clinical
      detail that administrative claims often lack, including laboratory
      values, disease severity markers, and clinical notes that are
      essential when outcome ascertainment depends on timing and
      clinical context. The study population includes adults (age 18 and
      older) with moderate-to-severe AD confirmed by ICD-10 diagnostic
      codes and baseline EASI scores of 16 or higher, who initiated
      either dupilumab or conventional systemic therapy between 2020 and
      2025. At least one baseline and one follow-up PRO assessment are
      required. Exclusion criteria are concurrent use of other biologic
      agents, participation in interventional clinical trials during the
      study period, and diagnoses of other inflammatory skin conditions
      that could confound outcome assessment.</p>
          <p>DLQI and PHQ-9 will be extracted from routine clinical
      assessments documented at baseline and follow-up visits. Both
      instruments have established reliability, validity, and
      responsiveness, and both are widely used in clinical practice,
      which helps maximize data availability and minimize respondent
      burden. Additional data elements include demographics (age, sex,
      race/ethnicity), EASI scores, treatment history (number of prior
      systemic therapies), comorbidities including prior
      depression/anxiety diagnoses, insurance type, and socioeconomic
      indicators.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="variables-and-measurement">
          <title>2.3.4 Variables and measurement</title>
          <fig id="tbl-variables">
            <caption>
              <p>Table 1: Study variables and
        measurement</p>
            </caption>
            <table-wrap>
              <table>
                <colgroup>
                  <col width="20%"/>
                  <col width="20%"/>
                  <col width="20%"/>
                  <col width="20%"/>
                  <col width="20%"/>
                </colgroup>
                <thead>
                  <tr>
                    <th>Variable Type</th>
                    <th>Variable</th>
                    <th>Description</th>
                    <th>Measurement</th>
                    <th>Scale</th>
                  </tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Primary Exposure</td>
                    <td>Treatment group</td>
                    <td>Dupilumab vs. conventional therapy</td>
                    <td>EHR prescription records</td>
                    <td>Categorical</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Primary Outcome</td>
                    <td>Disease-specific QoL</td>
                    <td>DLQI change score (baseline to 12 months)</td>
                    <td>Range: 0-30</td>
                    <td>Continuous</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Primary Outcome</td>
                    <td>Depressive symptoms</td>
                    <td>PHQ-9 change score (baseline to 12 months)</td>
                    <td>Range: 0-27</td>
                    <td>Continuous</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Confounder</td>
                    <td>Age</td>
                    <td>Patient age at enrollment</td>
                    <td>Years</td>
                    <td>Continuous</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Confounder</td>
                    <td>Sex</td>
                    <td>Male or female</td>
                    <td>Self-report</td>
                    <td>Categorical</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Confounder</td>
                    <td>Race/ethnicity</td>
                    <td>Race/ethnic group</td>
                    <td>EHR demographics</td>
                    <td>Categorical</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Confounder</td>
                    <td>Baseline EASI score</td>
                    <td>Disease severity at enrollment</td>
                    <td>Range: 0-72</td>
                    <td>Continuous</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Confounder</td>
                    <td>Treatment history</td>
                    <td>Prior systemic therapies</td>
                    <td>Count</td>
                    <td>Continuous</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Confounder</td>
                    <td>Disease duration</td>
                    <td>Years since AD diagnosis</td>
                    <td>Years</td>
                    <td>Continuous</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Confounder</td>
                    <td>Insurance status</td>
                    <td>Private, Medicare/Medicaid, or other</td>
                    <td>EHR records</td>
                    <td>Categorical</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Confounder</td>
                    <td>Depression/anxiety history</td>
                    <td>Documented prior diagnosis</td>
                    <td>ICD codes</td>
                    <td>Categorical</td>
                  </tr>
                </tbody>
              </table>
            </table-wrap>
          </fig>
        </sec>
        <sec id="mediating-moderating-and-confounding-relationships">
          <title>2.3.5 Mediating, moderating, and confounding
      relationships</title>
          <p>These three variable roles are frequently conflated but require
      different analytic strategies. A mediator is caused by the
      exposure and carries some portion of its effect to the outcome.
      Disease activity (EASI score change), itch intensity, and sleep
      disturbance are the hypothesized mediators in this framework.
      These will not be adjusted for in the primary analysis because
      conditioning on a mediator blocks the causal pathway through which
      treatment produces its effect, biasing the estimate toward the
      null.</p>
          <p>A moderator changes the strength or direction of the
      treatment-outcome relationship and is sometimes called an effect
      modifier. Age, sex, and baseline disease severity are the
      hypothesized moderators, examined through prespecified interaction
      terms in Aim 3. A moderator does not need to be associated with
      the exposure. It only needs to change the exposure’s effect on the
      outcome.</p>
          <p>A confounder is associated with both treatment selection and
      outcomes but does not lie on the causal pathway. Confounders must
      be measured before exposure to avoid conditioning on
      post-treatment variables that could introduce bias. Insurance
      status, disease duration, treatment history, depression/anxiety
      history, and socioeconomic status are all confounders and will be
      included in the propensity score model.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="statistical-analysis-plan">
          <title>2.3.6 Statistical analysis plan</title>
          <p><bold>Propensity score estimation.</bold> A propensity score is
      the probability that a patient received a particular treatment
      given their observed baseline characteristics. It compresses
      multiple confounders into a single score between zero and one and
      functions as a balancing score: patients with similar scores have,
      on average, similar distributions of observed covariates
      regardless of which treatment they received. Propensity scores
      will be estimated via logistic regression with treatment group as
      the dependent variable and the following baseline covariates as
      predictors: age, sex, race/ethnicity, baseline EASI score, number
      of prior systemic therapy failures, disease duration, insurance
      type, depression/anxiety history, and relevant comorbidities.
      Variable selection is based on subject matter knowledge of likely
      confounders. After weighting, covariate balance will be assessed
      using standardized mean differences (threshold: SMD &lt; 0.1) and
      propensity score overlap will be inspected visually to evaluate
      the positivity assumption, which requires a nonzero probability of
      receiving each treatment for every combination of covariates
      (<xref alt="Austin 2011" rid="ref-austin_introduction_2011" ref-type="bibr">Austin
      2011</xref>).</p>
          <p><bold>Primary analysis.</bold> The average treatment effect on
      the treated (ATT) will be estimated using IPTW in weighted linear
      regression models. IPTW creates a pseudo-population in which
      measured covariates are balanced across treatment groups,
      approximating what randomization would achieve. Primary outcomes
      are 12-month change scores for DLQI and PHQ-9. Point estimates
      will be reported with 95% confidence intervals, and clinical
      significance will be evaluated against established MCIDs (DLQI: 4
      points; PHQ-9: 5 points), focusing on whether confidence intervals
      exclude these thresholds and what effect sizes remain compatible
      with the data. Hypothesis testing at alpha = 0.05 will be
      reported, though a point estimate paired with its confidence
      interval is more informative for guiding treatment decisions than
      a binary significance label.</p>
          <p><bold>Effect modification analysis (Aim 3).</bold> Prespecified
      interaction terms for age, sex, and race will be included in
      regression models. Effect modification is established through the
      interaction test itself, not by comparing significance labels
      across subgroups. Stratum-specific effect sizes and confidence
      intervals will be reported to characterize the pattern of
      heterogeneity. Insurance status and socioeconomic factors will be
      examined as exploratory moderators.</p>
          <p><bold>Missing data.</bold> Missing data will be handled using
      multiple imputation by chained equations (MICE), under the
      assumption that data are missing at random conditional on observed
      covariates
      (<xref alt="White, Royston, and Wood 2011" rid="ref-white_multiple_2011" ref-type="bibr">White,
      Royston, and Wood 2011</xref>). Because EHR data often exhibit
      missingness that is not completely at random, sensitivity analyses
      will compare imputed results to complete-case analyses.
      Substantial divergence between approaches will prompt more
      cautious interpretation.</p>
          <p><bold>Sensitivity and robustness analyses.</bold> Three
      robustness checks are planned: (1) propensity score matching (1:1
      nearest-neighbor with caliper of 0.2 standard deviations of the
      logit of the propensity score) as an alternative to weighting; (2)
      doubly robust estimation combining IPTW with outcome regression,
      which remains consistent as long as at least one of the two models
      is correctly specified; and (3) E-value calculations to quantify
      the minimum strength of association that an unmeasured confounder
      would need to have with both treatment and outcome to explain away
      observed effects
      (<xref alt="VanderWeele and Ding 2017" rid="ref-vanderweele_sensitivity_2017" ref-type="bibr">VanderWeele
      and Ding 2017</xref>). The three assumptions underlying causal
      inference (exchangeability, positivity, and consistency) will be
      explicitly evaluated and discussed.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="influence-of-age-sex-and-race">
          <title>2.3.7 Influence of age, sex, and race</title>
          <p>Demographic characteristics are likely to shape both treatment
      patterns and outcomes. Older versus younger adults may have
      different baseline quality of life and depressive symptom
      profiles, and age-related variation in insurance coverage and
      formulary restrictions may affect the probability of receiving
      dupilumab. Sex differences may emerge in how patients perceive and
      report quality of life and mood symptoms over follow-up. Race may
      relate to disparities in treatment access, with differences in
      insurance coverage, referral patterns, and prior authorization
      requirements creating selection effects in who receives biologic
      versus conventional therapy
      (<xref alt="Tackett et al. 2020" rid="ref-tackett_structural_2020" ref-type="bibr">Tackett
      et al. 2020</xref>). All three variables will enter the propensity
      score model as covariates, and interaction analyses (Aim 3) will
      evaluate whether treatment effects differ across demographic
      subgroups. Stratum-specific results will be interpreted through
      effect sizes and confidence intervals rather than significance
      labels alone.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="potential-challenges-and-solutions">
          <title>2.3.8 Potential challenges and solutions</title>
          <fig id="tbl-challenges">
            <caption>
              <p>Table 2: Potential challenges and proposed
        solutions</p>
            </caption>
            <table-wrap>
              <table>
                <colgroup>
                  <col width="38%"/>
                  <col width="62%"/>
                </colgroup>
                <thead>
                  <tr>
                    <th>Challenge</th>
                    <th>Proposed Solution</th>
                  </tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Confounding by indication: dupilumab patients have
                more severe, refractory disease</td>
                    <td>IPTW with thorough covariate balance assessment (SMD
                &lt; 0.1); doubly robust estimation as sensitivity
                analysis; E-value calculations for unmeasured
                confounding</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Missing PRO data from incomplete follow-up or
                inconsistent EHR documentation</td>
                    <td>Multiple imputation by chained equations with
                sensitivity analyses comparing complete-case results;
                evaluation of whether missingness patterns relate to
                patient characteristics or outcome risk</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Selection bias from differential out-of-pocket costs
                affecting who receives dupilumab</td>
                    <td>Include insurance status and socioeconomic
                indicators in propensity score model; assess residual
                imbalance post-weighting</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Treatment switching or discontinuation during
                follow-up</td>
                    <td>Intention-to-treat analysis as primary approach;
                per-protocol analysis as sensitivity check with
                documented switching rates and reasons</td>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Insufficient sample size for subgroup analyses by
                race</td>
                    <td>Report stratum-specific estimates with confidence
                intervals; acknowledge precision limitations
                transparently; avoid interpreting nonsignificance as
                absence of effect</td>
                  </tr>
                </tbody>
              </table>
            </table-wrap>
          </fig>
        </sec>
        <sec id="study-timeline">
          <title>2.3.9 Study timeline</title>
          <fig id="tbl-timeline">
            <caption>
              <p>Table 3: Study timeline</p>
            </caption>
            <table-wrap>
              <table>
                <thead>
                  <tr>
                    <th>Activity</th>
                    <th align="center">Year 1 Q1-Q2</th>
                    <th align="center">Year 1 Q3-Q4</th>
                    <th align="center">Year 2 Q1-Q2</th>
                    <th align="center">Year 2 Q3-Q4</th>
                  </tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                  <tr>
                    <td>IRB approval and data access agreements</td>
                    <td align="center">✓</td>
                    <td align="center"/>
                    <td align="center"/>
                    <td align="center"/>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Cohort identification and data extraction</td>
                    <td align="center">✓</td>
                    <td align="center">✓</td>
                    <td align="center"/>
                    <td align="center"/>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Propensity score estimation and balance
                assessment</td>
                    <td align="center"/>
                    <td align="center">✓</td>
                    <td align="center"/>
                    <td align="center"/>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Primary analyses (Aims 1 and 2)</td>
                    <td align="center"/>
                    <td align="center">✓</td>
                    <td align="center">✓</td>
                    <td align="center"/>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Effect modification analyses (Aim 3)</td>
                    <td align="center"/>
                    <td align="center"/>
                    <td align="center">✓</td>
                    <td align="center"/>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Sensitivity analyses and robustness checks</td>
                    <td align="center"/>
                    <td align="center"/>
                    <td align="center">✓</td>
                    <td align="center"/>
                  </tr>
                  <tr>
                    <td>Manuscript preparation and dissemination</td>
                    <td align="center"/>
                    <td align="center"/>
                    <td align="center">✓</td>
                    <td align="center">✓</td>
                  </tr>
                </tbody>
              </table>
            </table-wrap>
          </fig>
          <p/>
        </sec>
      </sec>
    </sec>
  </body>
  <back>
    <ref-list>
      <title>3. References</title>
      <ref id="ref-afshari_unraveling_2024">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Afshari</surname>
              <given-names>Moeina</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kolackova</surname>
              <given-names>Martina</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Rosecka</surname>
              <given-names>Michaela</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Čelakovská</surname>
              <given-names>Jarmila</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Krejsek</surname>
              <given-names>Jan</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Unraveling the skin; a comprehensive review of atopic dermatitis, current understanding, and approaches</article-title>
          <source>Front Immunol</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2024">2024</year>
          <volume>15</volume>
          <issn>1664-3224</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2024.1361005</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38500882</pub-id>
          <fpage>1361005</fpage>
          <lpage/>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-austin_introduction_2011">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Austin</surname>
              <given-names>Peter C.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>An Introduction to Propensity Score Methods for Reducing the Effects of Confounding in Observational Studies</article-title>
          <source>Multivariate Behav Res</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2011-05">2011</year>
          <month>05</month>
          <volume>46</volume>
          <issue>3</issue>
          <issn>1532-7906</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/00273171.2011.568786</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21818162</pub-id>
          <fpage>399</fpage>
          <lpage>424</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-chopra_assessing_2018">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Chopra</surname>
              <given-names>Rishi</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Silverberg</surname>
              <given-names>Jonathan I.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Assessing the severity of atopic dermatitis in clinical trials and practice</article-title>
          <source>Clin Dermatol</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2018">2018</year>
          <volume>36</volume>
          <issue>5</issue>
          <issn>1879-1131</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.clindermatol.2018.05.012</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30217273</pub-id>
          <fpage>606</fpage>
          <lpage>615</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-drucker_burden_2017">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Drucker</surname>
              <given-names>Aaron M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wang</surname>
              <given-names>Annie R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Li</surname>
              <given-names>Wen-Qing</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Sevetson</surname>
              <given-names>Erika</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Block</surname>
              <given-names>Julie K.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Qureshi</surname>
              <given-names>Abrar A.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>The Burden of Atopic Dermatitis: Summary of a Report for the National Eczema Association</article-title>
          <source>J Invest Dermatol</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2017-01">2017</year>
          <month>01</month>
          <volume>137</volume>
          <issue>1</issue>
          <issn>1523-1747</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jid.2016.07.012</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27616422</pub-id>
          <fpage>26</fpage>
          <lpage>30</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-eckert_impact_2017">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Eckert</surname>
              <given-names>Laurent</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Gupta</surname>
              <given-names>Shaloo</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Amand</surname>
              <given-names>Caroline</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Gadkari</surname>
              <given-names>Abhijit</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Mahajan</surname>
              <given-names>Puneet</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Gelfand</surname>
              <given-names>Joel M.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Impact of atopic dermatitis on health-related quality of life and productivity in adults in the United States: An analysis using the National Health and Wellness Survey</article-title>
          <source>J Am Acad Dermatol</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2017-08">2017</year>
          <month>08</month>
          <volume>77</volume>
          <issue>2</issue>
          <issn>1097-6787</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2017.04.019</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28606711</pub-id>
          <fpage>274</fpage>
          <lpage>279.e3</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-finlay_dermatology_1994">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Finlay</surname>
              <given-names>A. Y.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Khan</surname>
              <given-names>G. K.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI)–a simple practical measure for routine clinical use</article-title>
          <source>Clin Exp Dermatol</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="1994-05">1994</year>
          <month>05</month>
          <volume>19</volume>
          <issue>3</issue>
          <issn>0307-6938</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2230.1994.tb01167.x</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8033378</pub-id>
          <fpage>210</fpage>
          <lpage>216</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-kroenke_phq-9_2001">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Kroenke</surname>
              <given-names>Kurt</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Spitzer</surname>
              <given-names>Robert L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Williams</surname>
              <given-names>Janet B. W.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>The PHQ-9</article-title>
          <source>J GEN INTERN MED</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2001-09">2001</year>
          <month>09</month>
          <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
            <year iso-8601-date="2026-04-15">2026</year>
            <month>04</month>
            <day>15</day>
          </date-in-citation>
          <volume>16</volume>
          <issue>9</issue>
          <issn>1525-1497</issn>
          <uri>https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1525-1497.2001.016009606.x</uri>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1046/j.1525-1497.2001.016009606.x</pub-id>
          <fpage>606</fpage>
          <lpage>613</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-eichenfield_guidelines_2014">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Eichenfield</surname>
              <given-names>Lawrence F.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Tom</surname>
              <given-names>Wynnis L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Berger</surname>
              <given-names>Timothy G.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Krol</surname>
              <given-names>Alfons</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Paller</surname>
              <given-names>Amy S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Schwarzenberger</surname>
              <given-names>Kathryn</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Bergman</surname>
              <given-names>James N.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chamlin</surname>
              <given-names>Sarah L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Cohen</surname>
              <given-names>David E.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Cooper</surname>
              <given-names>Kevin D.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Cordoro</surname>
              <given-names>Kelly M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Davis</surname>
              <given-names>Dawn M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Feldman</surname>
              <given-names>Steven R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hanifin</surname>
              <given-names>Jon M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Margolis</surname>
              <given-names>David J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Silverman</surname>
              <given-names>Robert A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Simpson</surname>
              <given-names>Eric L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Williams</surname>
              <given-names>Hywel C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Elmets</surname>
              <given-names>Craig A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Block</surname>
              <given-names>Julie</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Harrod</surname>
              <given-names>Christopher G.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Smith Begolka</surname>
              <given-names>Wendy</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Sidbury</surname>
              <given-names>Robert</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Guidelines of care for the management of atopic dermatitis: Section 2. Management and treatment of atopic dermatitis with topical therapies</article-title>
          <source>J Am Acad Dermatol</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2014-07">2014</year>
          <month>07</month>
          <volume>71</volume>
          <issue>1</issue>
          <issn>1097-6787</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2014.03.023</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24813302</pub-id>
          <fpage>116</fpage>
          <lpage>132</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-silverberg_adult_2013">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Silverberg</surname>
              <given-names>Jonathan I.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hanifin</surname>
              <given-names>Jon M.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Adult eczema prevalence and associations with asthma and other health and demographic factors: A US population-based study</article-title>
          <source>J Allergy Clin Immunol</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2013-11">2013</year>
          <month>11</month>
          <volume>132</volume>
          <issue>5</issue>
          <issn>1097-6825</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2013.08.031</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24094544</pub-id>
          <fpage>1132</fpage>
          <lpage>1138</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-silverberg_patient_2018">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Silverberg</surname>
              <given-names>Jonathan I.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Gelfand</surname>
              <given-names>Joel M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Margolis</surname>
              <given-names>David J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Boguniewicz</surname>
              <given-names>Mark</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Fonacier</surname>
              <given-names>Luz</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Grayson</surname>
              <given-names>Mitchell H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Simpson</surname>
              <given-names>Eric L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ong</surname>
              <given-names>Peck Y.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chiesa Fuxench</surname>
              <given-names>Zelma C.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Patient burden and quality of life in atopic dermatitis in US adults: A population-based cross-sectional study</article-title>
          <source>Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2018-09">2018</year>
          <month>09</month>
          <volume>121</volume>
          <issue>3</issue>
          <issn>1534-4436</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.anai.2018.07.006</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30025911</pub-id>
          <fpage>340</fpage>
          <lpage>347</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-simpson_two_2016">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Simpson</surname>
              <given-names>Eric L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Bieber</surname>
              <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Guttman-Yassky</surname>
              <given-names>Emma</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Beck</surname>
              <given-names>Lisa A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Blauvelt</surname>
              <given-names>Andrew</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Cork</surname>
              <given-names>Michael J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Silverberg</surname>
              <given-names>Jonathan I.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Deleuran</surname>
              <given-names>Mette</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kataoka</surname>
              <given-names>Yoko</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lacour</surname>
              <given-names>Jean-Philippe</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kingo</surname>
              <given-names>Külli</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Worm</surname>
              <given-names>Margitta</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Poulin</surname>
              <given-names>Yves</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wollenberg</surname>
              <given-names>Andreas</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Soo</surname>
              <given-names>Yuhwen</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Graham</surname>
              <given-names>Neil M. H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Pirozzi</surname>
              <given-names>Gianluca</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Akinlade</surname>
              <given-names>Bolanle</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Staudinger</surname>
              <given-names>Heribert</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Mastey</surname>
              <given-names>Vera</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Eckert</surname>
              <given-names>Laurent</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Gadkari</surname>
              <given-names>Abhijit</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Stahl</surname>
              <given-names>Neil</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Yancopoulos</surname>
              <given-names>George D.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ardeleanu</surname>
              <given-names>Marius</given-names>
            </name>
            <string-name>SOLO 1 and SOLO 2 Investigators</string-name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Two Phase 3 Trials of Dupilumab versus Placebo in Atopic Dermatitis</article-title>
          <source>N Engl J Med</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2016-12">2016</year>
          <month>12</month>
          <volume>375</volume>
          <issue>24</issue>
          <issn>1533-4406</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1610020</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27690741</pub-id>
          <fpage>2335</fpage>
          <lpage>2348</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-tackett_structural_2020">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Tackett</surname>
              <given-names>Kelly Jo</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Jenkins</surname>
              <given-names>Frances</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Morrell</surname>
              <given-names>Dean S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>McShane</surname>
              <given-names>Diana B.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Burkhart</surname>
              <given-names>Craig N.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Structural racism and its influence on the severity of atopic dermatitis in African American children</article-title>
          <source>Pediatr Dermatol</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2020-01">2020</year>
          <month>01</month>
          <volume>37</volume>
          <issue>1</issue>
          <issn>1525-1470</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/pde.14058</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31854003</pub-id>
          <fpage>142</fpage>
          <lpage>146</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-vanderweele_sensitivity_2017">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>VanderWeele</surname>
              <given-names>Tyler J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ding</surname>
              <given-names>Peng</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Sensitivity Analysis in Observational Research: Introducing the E-Value</article-title>
          <source>Ann Intern Med</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2017-08">2017</year>
          <month>08</month>
          <volume>167</volume>
          <issue>4</issue>
          <issn>1539-3704</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7326/M16-2607</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28693043</pub-id>
          <fpage>268</fpage>
          <lpage>274</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-yu_systematic_2018">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Yu</surname>
              <given-names>Sherry H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Drucker</surname>
              <given-names>Aaron M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lebwohl</surname>
              <given-names>Mark</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Silverberg</surname>
              <given-names>Jonathan I.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>A systematic review of the safety and efficacy of systemic corticosteroids in atopic dermatitis</article-title>
          <source>J Am Acad Dermatol</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2018-04">2018</year>
          <month>04</month>
          <volume>78</volume>
          <issue>4</issue>
          <issn>1097-6787</issn>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2017.09.074</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29032119</pub-id>
          <fpage>733</fpage>
          <lpage>740.e11</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-basra_determining_2015">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Basra</surname>
              <given-names>M. K. A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Salek</surname>
              <given-names>M. S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Camilleri</surname>
              <given-names>L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Sturkey</surname>
              <given-names>R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Finlay</surname>
              <given-names>A. Y.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Determining the minimal clinically important difference and responsiveness of the Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI): Further data</article-title>
          <source>Dermatology</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2015">2015</year>
          <volume>230</volume>
          <issue>1</issue>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1159/000365390</pub-id>
          <fpage>27</fpage>
          <lpage>33</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="ref-white_multiple_2011">
        <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>White</surname>
              <given-names>Ian R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Royston</surname>
              <given-names>Patrick</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wood</surname>
              <given-names>Angela M.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Multiple imputation using chained equations: Issues and guidance for practice</article-title>
          <source>Stat Med</source>
          <year iso-8601-date="2011">2011</year>
          <volume>30</volume>
          <issue>4</issue>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/sim.4067</pub-id>
          <fpage>377</fpage>
          <lpage>399</lpage>
        </element-citation>
      </ref>
    </ref-list>
  </back>
  <sub-article article-type="notebook" id="nb-2-nb-article">
    <front-stub>
      <title-group>
        <article-title>Comparing Patient-Reported Outcomes Between Dupilumab and
Conventional Therapy in Adults with Moderate-to-Severe Atopic
Dermatitis</article-title>
        <subtitle>HPO 677 Final Project - NIH Grant Proposal
(PAR-24-280)</subtitle>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes">
          <name>
            <surname>Neri</surname>
            <given-names>Louie</given-names>
          </name>
          <string-name>Louie Neri</string-name>
          <xref ref-type="corresp" rid="cor-1-nb-article">*</xref>
        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <author-notes>
        <corresp id="cor-1-nb-article"/>
      </author-notes>
      <abstract>
        <p>This grant proposal compares patient-reported outcomes between
dupilumab and conventional therapy in adults with moderate-to-severe
atopic dermatitis using observational electronic health record data.</p>
      </abstract>
    </front-stub>
    <body>
      <sec specific-use="notebook-content">
        <code language="r script">library(tidyverse)</code>
        <boxed-text>
          <preformat>── Attaching core tidyverse packages ──────────────────────── tidyverse 2.0.0 ──
✔ dplyr     1.1.4     ✔ readr     2.1.5
✔ forcats   1.0.0     ✔ stringr   1.5.1
✔ ggplot2   3.5.2     ✔ tibble    3.2.1
✔ lubridate 1.9.3     ✔ tidyr     1.3.1
✔ purrr     1.0.2     
── Conflicts ────────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse_conflicts() ──
✖ dplyr::filter() masks stats::filter()
✖ dplyr::lag()    masks stats::lag()
ℹ Use the conflicted package (&lt;http://conflicted.r-lib.org/&gt;) to force all conflicts to become errors</preformat>
        </boxed-text>
        <code language="r script">library(ggdag)</code>
        <boxed-text>
          <preformat>
Attaching package: 'ggdag'

The following object is masked from 'package:stats':

    filter</preformat>
        </boxed-text>
      </sec>
      <sec id="specific-aims-nb-article">
        <title>1. Specific Aims</title>
        <p>Atopic dermatitis (AD) is a chronic inflammatory skin condition
  affecting an estimated 7% to 10% of adults in the United States
  (<xref alt="Silverberg and Hanifin 2013" rid="ref-silverberg_adult_2013-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Silverberg
  and Hanifin 2013</xref>). Moderate-to-severe AD produces persistent
  pruritus, sleep disturbance, visible skin changes, and psychological
  distress, which together reduce quality of life and elevate the risk
  of depression and anxiety
  (<xref alt="Silverberg et al. 2018" rid="ref-silverberg_patient_2018-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Silverberg
  et al. 2018</xref>). The disease burden experienced by patients
  extends well beyond what clinical severity scores capture.</p>
        <p>Dupilumab, a biologic therapy targeting IL-4 and IL-13 signaling,
  has reshaped the treatment landscape for moderate-to-severe AD since
  its FDA approval in 2017
  (<xref alt="Simpson et al. 2016" rid="ref-simpson_two_2016-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Simpson
  et al. 2016</xref>). The evidence supporting its use, however, comes
  largely from randomized controlled trials with restrictive eligibility
  criteria. These trials typically exclude older adults, patients with
  multiple comorbidities, and those on concurrent medications, which
  limits how well their findings translate to routine clinical practice.
  Real-world data comparing patient-reported outcomes (PROs) between
  dupilumab and conventional therapy remain sparse, particularly over
  the 12-month time horizon relevant to clinical decision-making
  (<xref alt="Afshari et al. 2024" rid="ref-afshari_unraveling_2024-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Afshari
  et al. 2024</xref>).</p>
        <p>This gap matters for three reasons. First, clinicians and patients
  making treatment decisions lack robust comparative data on outcomes
  that reflect what patients actually experience. Second, cost
  differences between biologic and conventional therapies are
  substantial. Out-of-pocket costs for dupilumab can reach several
  thousand dollars per year depending on insurance coverage, and the
  resulting financial burden can independently worsen depressive
  symptoms even when skin symptoms improve
  (<xref alt="Drucker et al. 2017" rid="ref-drucker_burden_2017-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Drucker
  et al. 2017</xref>). Third, understanding these trade-offs is
  essential for shared decision-making that reflects both clinical
  effectiveness and the patient-centered consequences of treatment
  choice.</p>
        <p>The long-term goal of this research is to generate real-world
  evidence on patient-centered outcomes that can inform treatment
  selection and health policy for adults with moderate-to-severe AD. The
  objective of this application is to compare changes in
  disease-specific quality of life and depressive symptoms between
  patients initiating dupilumab versus conventional therapy over 12
  months, using electronic health record (EHR) data from a large
  academic medical center. The underlying rationale is that
  observational data reflecting real-world clinical pathways complement
  trial evidence and identify outcomes meaningful to patients, which
  supports the design of future clinical studies. This proposal responds
  to PAR-24-280, Clinical Observational Studies in Musculoskeletal,
  Rheumatic, and Skin Diseases, which seeks well-designed observational
  research that improves understanding of disease symptoms and outcomes
  important to patients with skin conditions.</p>
        <p>The specific aims are:</p>
        <p><bold>Aim 1: Compare 12-month changes in disease-specific quality
  of life between dupilumab and conventional therapy.</bold> Changes in
  the Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI)
  (<xref alt="Finlay and Khan 1994" rid="ref-finlay_dermatology_1994-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Finlay
  and Khan 1994</xref>) will be evaluated between treatment groups, with
  confounding by indication addressed through inverse probability of
  treatment weighting (IPTW). The working hypothesis is that
  dupilumab-treated patients will show greater DLQI improvement than
  those on conventional therapy, with differences exceeding the minimal
  clinically important difference (MCID) of 4 points
  (<xref alt="Basra et al. 2015" rid="ref-basra_determining_2015-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Basra
  et al. 2015</xref>).</p>
        <p><bold>Aim 2: Compare 12-month changes in depressive symptoms
  between dupilumab and conventional therapy.</bold> Changes in the
  Patient Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9)
  (<xref alt="Kroenke, Spitzer, and Williams 2001" rid="ref-kroenke_phq-9_2001-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Kroenke,
  Spitzer, and Williams 2001</xref>) will be evaluated between treatment
  groups using the same IPTW approach. The hypothesis is that
  dupilumab-treated patients will show greater reductions in depressive
  symptoms, consistent with the established relationship between skin
  disease burden and psychological well-being.</p>
        <p><bold>Aim 3: Examine whether treatment effects vary by age, sex,
  and race.</bold> Prespecified interaction terms will test for effect
  modification by demographic characteristics. This aim will identify
  subgroups that may experience differential benefits and will surface
  potential disparities in treatment outcomes. Insurance status and
  socioeconomic factors will be examined as exploratory moderators.</p>
        <p>The expected output is real-world comparative effectiveness
  evidence on patient-reported outcomes in AD that is directly relevant
  to clinical decision-making. Secondary contributions include
  characterizing disease symptom trajectories under routine care,
  supporting the use of DLQI and PHQ-9 as endpoints in future clinical
  studies, and identifying sources of treatment effect heterogeneity
  that can inform efforts to reduce disparities in AD care. This work
  aligns with the NIAMS mission to improve outcomes and function in
  patients with skin conditions.</p>
        <p/>
      </sec>
      <sec id="research-strategy-nb-article">
        <title>2. Research Strategy</title>
        <sec id="significance-nb-article">
          <title>2.1 Significance</title>
          <sec id="burden-of-atopic-dermatitis-nb-article">
            <title>2.1.1 Burden of atopic dermatitis</title>
            <p>AD is the most common chronic inflammatory skin disease and
      affects a substantial proportion of US adults
      (<xref alt="Silverberg and Hanifin 2013" rid="ref-silverberg_adult_2013-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Silverberg
      and Hanifin 2013</xref>). The condition is characterized by
      intense pruritus, erythematous and excoriated lesions, and a
      relapsing-remitting course that meaningfully diminishes quality of
      life. The associated sleep disturbance, social stigma, impaired
      work productivity, and elevated rates of depression and anxiety
      amplify this burden considerably
      (<xref alt="Yu et al. 2018" rid="ref-yu_systematic_2018-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Yu
      et al. 2018</xref>). The psychosocial impact of moderate-to-severe
      AD can be comparable to that of asthma and diabetes
      (<xref alt="Eckert et al. 2017" rid="ref-eckert_impact_2017-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Eckert
      et al. 2017</xref>), and the outcomes patients care about most are
      experiential: how the disease affects daily activities,
      relationships, and emotional well-being rather than the specific
      values on a clinical severity scale.</p>
          </sec>
          <sec id="treatment-options-and-the-limits-of-current-evidence-nb-article">
            <title>2.1.2 Treatment options and the limits of current
      evidence</title>
            <p>Conventional therapy includes topical corticosteroids,
      calcineurin inhibitors, and systemic immunosuppressants such as
      cyclosporine, methotrexate, and mycophenolate mofetil. These
      agents can reduce disease severity but carry risks of long-term
      toxicity and yield variable efficacy
      (<xref alt="Eichenfield et al. 2014" rid="ref-eichenfield_guidelines_2014-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Eichenfield
      et al. 2014</xref>). Dupilumab, the first FDA-approved biologic
      for AD, has demonstrated efficacy in pivotal randomized trials
      (<xref alt="Simpson et al. 2016" rid="ref-simpson_two_2016-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Simpson
      et al. 2016</xref>). Those trials, however, enrolled highly
      selected populations under controlled conditions. Their findings
      do not necessarily extend to the broader population seen in
      routine practice, where adherence is lower, comorbidities are
      common, and clinical monitoring is less frequent.</p>
          </sec>
          <sec id="gaps-in-patient-reported-outcomes-evidence-nb-article">
            <title>2.1.3 Gaps in patient-reported outcomes evidence</title>
            <p>Despite growing adoption of dupilumab, head-to-head
      observational comparisons of patient-reported outcomes between
      biologic and conventional therapy in real-world settings remain
      limited. Most existing studies rely on clinician-assessed severity
      scores such as EASI and SCORAD
      (<xref alt="Chopra and Silverberg 2018" rid="ref-chopra_assessing_2018-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Chopra
      and Silverberg 2018</xref>). Clinical severity captures important
      biological information but does not reflect the full scope of what
      patients experience. DLQI was chosen for this study because it is
      a condition-specific instrument that captures the particular
      impact of skin disease on daily life, and because
      condition-specific measures tend to be more responsive to
      treatment-related change than generic measures when a real
      treatment effect is present. PHQ-9 adds a complementary dimension
      by capturing depressive symptom burden, which is a recognized
      comorbidity that amplifies overall disease impact. The pairing of
      these two instruments produces a more complete picture of how
      treatments affect patients than either clinical severity scores or
      generic health measures alone.</p>
          </sec>
          <sec id="financial-toxicity-and-access-disparities-nb-article">
            <title>2.1.4 Financial toxicity and access disparities</title>
            <p>Out-of-pocket costs for dupilumab vary widely depending on
      insurance coverage, ranging from minimal copayments to several
      thousand dollars annually
      (<xref alt="Drucker et al. 2017" rid="ref-drucker_burden_2017-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Drucker
      et al. 2017</xref>). This variation creates selection effects in
      who receives biologic therapy, with implications for both the
      internal validity of observational comparisons and for health
      equity. Financial burden can also independently worsen depression
      scores and reduce adherence, potentially attenuating treatment
      benefits regardless of pharmacologic efficacy. These cost-related
      dynamics must be accounted for when interpreting PRO differences
      between treatment groups and when designing future studies that
      address economic barriers to care.</p>
          </sec>
          <sec id="importance-to-the-field-nb-article">
            <title>2.1.5 Importance to the field</title>
            <p>By generating the kind of observational evidence that
      PAR-24-280 is designed to support, this project will provide data
      that directly inform the design of future clinical studies in AD,
      including identification of appropriate primary endpoints and
      characterization of the subgroups most likely to benefit from
      biologic therapy.</p>
          </sec>
        </sec>
        <sec id="innovation-nb-article">
          <title>2.2 Innovation</title>
          <p>This proposal advances the field in five respects.</p>
          <p><italic>Dual patient-reported outcome focus.</italic> Existing
    comparative studies of AD treatments have predominantly relied on
    clinician-assessed severity endpoints
    (<xref alt="Chopra and Silverberg 2018" rid="ref-chopra_assessing_2018-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Chopra
    and Silverberg 2018</xref>). Centering this study on two validated
    patient-reported instruments as co-primary outcomes shifts the
    evidentiary focus toward what patients experience. DLQI captures
    disease-specific impact on daily life and has strong responsiveness
    in dermatology populations; PHQ-9 captures psychological burden and
    is widely established for depression screening and severity
    assessment. Pairing a condition-specific instrument with a mental
    health instrument is uncommon in comparative AD research and
    reflects the multidimensional nature of disease impact.</p>
          <p><italic>Integration of mental health outcomes in dermatology
    research.</italic> Depression is a recognized comorbidity of AD
    (<xref alt="Yu et al. 2018" rid="ref-yu_systematic_2018-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Yu
    et al. 2018</xref>), but few observational studies have
    systematically tracked depressive symptom trajectories across
    treatment strategies. Including PHQ-9 as a primary endpoint
    alongside DLQI makes the psychological dimension of treatment
    benefit testable rather than assumed.</p>
          <p><italic>Systematic evaluation of treatment effect
    heterogeneity.</italic> A single average treatment effect can mask
    substantial variation across subgroups. This study formally tests
    whether benefits differ by age, sex, and race. Given documented
    disparities in AD treatment access across demographic groups
    (<xref alt="Tackett et al. 2020" rid="ref-tackett_structural_2020-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Tackett
    et al. 2020</xref>), this approach identifies subgroups that may
    experience differential benefits. Effect modification will be
    assessed through formal interaction tests rather than side-by-side
    comparison of significance labels across strata, the latter being a
    common but invalid way to establish that effects truly differ.</p>
          <p><italic>Methodological rigor in addressing confounding by
    indication.</italic> Patients receiving dupilumab typically have
    more severe, refractory disease than those on conventional therapy.
    IPTW will create a pseudo-population in which measured baseline
    covariates are balanced across treatment groups, and covariate
    balance will be verified through standardized mean differences
    (threshold: SMD &lt; 0.1) and propensity score overlap to evaluate
    positivity. E-value sensitivity analyses will quantify how strong an
    unmeasured confounder would need to be to explain away observed
    effects
    (<xref alt="VanderWeele and Ding 2017" rid="ref-vanderweele_sensitivity_2017-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">VanderWeele
    and Ding 2017</xref>). The combination provides a transparent
    framework for causal interpretation in an observational setting.</p>
          <p><italic>Emphasis on clinical meaningfulness.</italic>
    Interpretation will center on effect size, confidence interval
    width, and compatibility with established MCIDs (DLQI: 4 points,
    (<xref alt="Basra et al. 2015" rid="ref-basra_determining_2015-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Basra
    et al. 2015</xref>); PHQ-9: 5 points,
    (<xref alt="Kroenke, Spitzer, and Williams 2001" rid="ref-kroenke_phq-9_2001-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Kroenke,
    Spitzer, and Williams 2001</xref>)), rather than on whether a result
    crosses a p-value threshold. Statistically significant findings do
    not guarantee clinically important effects, particularly in large
    samples where small differences can produce low p-values.
    Nonsignificant findings in smaller samples may reflect imprecision
    rather than absence of effect. Interpretation grounded in effect
    magnitude and clinical thresholds is more useful for treatment
    decisions than a binary significance label.</p>
        </sec>
        <sec id="approach-nb-article">
          <title>2.3 Approach</title>
          <sec id="overview-and-conceptual-model-nb-article">
            <title>2.3.1 Overview and conceptual model</title>
            <p>This prospective cohort study will compare patient-reported
      outcomes between adults with moderate-to-severe AD initiating
      dupilumab versus conventional therapy. The conceptual model serves
      as the organizing framework: treatment type (the primary exposure)
      affects disease activity, itch intensity, and sleep disturbance,
      which in turn influence DLQI and PHQ-9. Confounders including
      baseline disease severity, treatment history, insurance status,
      comorbidities, and socioeconomic factors affect both treatment
      selection and outcomes and must be addressed through propensity
      score methods. The model assigns each variable an explicit role as
      exposure, mediator, moderator, or confounder, which prevents the
      analysis from devolving into a list of variables without rationale
      and ensures every analytic decision ties back to the hypothesized
      causal structure.</p>
            <sec id="cell-fig-conceptual-model-nb-article" specific-use="notebook-content">
              <code language="r script">library(tidyverse)

boxes &lt;- tibble(
  x = c(1, 4, 7, 4),
  y = c(1, 1, 1, 3),
  label = c(
    "Treatment\nDupilumab vs. Conventional",
    "Mediators\nDisease activity\nItch intensity\nSleep disturbance",
    "Outcomes\nDLQI\nPHQ-9",
    "Confounders\nBaseline severity\nTreatment history\nInsurance\nComorbidities\nSES\nAge\nSex\nRace"
  )
)

arrows &lt;- tibble(
  x = c(1.8, 4.8, 3.6, 4.4),
  y = c(1.0, 1.0, 2.7, 2.7),
  xend = c(3.2, 6.2, 1.8, 6.2),
  yend = c(1.0, 1.0, 1.4, 1.4)
)

ggplot() +
  geom_segment(
    data = arrows,
    aes(x = x, y = y, xend = xend, yend = yend),
    arrow = arrow(type = "closed"),
    color = "gray50"
  ) +
  geom_curve(
    aes(x = 1.5, y = 0.6, xend = 6.5, yend = 0.6),
    curvature = 0.2,
    arrow = arrow(type = "closed"),
    color = "gray50"
  ) +
  geom_label(
    data = boxes,
    aes(x = x, y = y, label = label),
    fill = "white"
  ) +
  annotate(
    "text",
    x = 4,
    y = 0.35,
    label = "direct effect",
    hjust = 0.5
  ) +
  coord_cartesian(xlim = c(0, 8), ylim = c(0, 4)) +
  theme_void()</code>
              <fig id="fig-conceptual-model-nb-article">
                <caption>
                  <p>Figure 1: Conceptual model. The primary causal
        pathway runs from treatment through mediators to outcomes.
        Confounders influence both treatment selection and outcomes,
        creating the need for propensity score adjustment.</p>
                </caption>
                <graphic mimetype="image" mime-subtype="png" xlink:href="index_files/figure-jats/fig-conceptual-model-1.png"/>
              </fig>
            </sec>
          </sec>
          <sec id="study-design-nb-article">
            <title>2.3.2 Study design</title>
            <p>A prospective cohort design is appropriate because randomizing
      patients to dupilumab versus conventional therapy is neither
      practical nor ethical. Dupilumab is typically prescribed after
      conventional options have failed, and insurance authorization
      creates natural treatment pathways that a research protocol cannot
      easily override. Two cohorts will be enrolled at treatment
      initiation and followed for 12 months, with PROs collected at
      baseline and at 3, 6, and 12 months. Prospective collection
      ensures standardized outcome measurement rather than reliance on
      inconsistently documented chart data.</p>
            <p>The principal threat to validity is confounding by indication.
      Dupilumab recipients tend to have more severe disease, meaning
      baseline differences between groups could bias observed
      associations. This is a structural problem that propensity score
      methods partially address for measured confounders but cannot
      address for unmeasured ones, which is why sensitivity analyses are
      essential.</p>
          </sec>
          <sec id="study-population-and-data-source-nb-article">
            <title>2.3.3 Study population and data source</title>
            <p>EHR data from a large academic medical center with an active
      dermatology specialty clinic will be used. EHR data add clinical
      detail that administrative claims often lack, including laboratory
      values, disease severity markers, and clinical notes that are
      essential when outcome ascertainment depends on timing and
      clinical context. The study population includes adults (age 18 and
      older) with moderate-to-severe AD confirmed by ICD-10 diagnostic
      codes and baseline EASI scores of 16 or higher, who initiated
      either dupilumab or conventional systemic therapy between 2020 and
      2025. At least one baseline and one follow-up PRO assessment are
      required. Exclusion criteria are concurrent use of other biologic
      agents, participation in interventional clinical trials during the
      study period, and diagnoses of other inflammatory skin conditions
      that could confound outcome assessment.</p>
            <p>DLQI and PHQ-9 will be extracted from routine clinical
      assessments documented at baseline and follow-up visits. Both
      instruments have established reliability, validity, and
      responsiveness, and both are widely used in clinical practice,
      which helps maximize data availability and minimize respondent
      burden. Additional data elements include demographics (age, sex,
      race/ethnicity), EASI scores, treatment history (number of prior
      systemic therapies), comorbidities including prior
      depression/anxiety diagnoses, insurance type, and socioeconomic
      indicators.</p>
          </sec>
          <sec id="variables-and-measurement-nb-article">
            <title>2.3.4 Variables and measurement</title>
            <fig id="tbl-variables-nb-article">
              <caption>
                <p>Table 1: Study variables and
        measurement</p>
              </caption>
              <table-wrap>
                <table>
                  <colgroup>
                    <col width="20%"/>
                    <col width="20%"/>
                    <col width="20%"/>
                    <col width="20%"/>
                    <col width="20%"/>
                  </colgroup>
                  <thead>
                    <tr>
                      <th>Variable Type</th>
                      <th>Variable</th>
                      <th>Description</th>
                      <th>Measurement</th>
                      <th>Scale</th>
                    </tr>
                  </thead>
                  <tbody>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Primary Exposure</td>
                      <td>Treatment group</td>
                      <td>Dupilumab vs. conventional therapy</td>
                      <td>EHR prescription records</td>
                      <td>Categorical</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Primary Outcome</td>
                      <td>Disease-specific QoL</td>
                      <td>DLQI change score (baseline to 12 months)</td>
                      <td>Range: 0-30</td>
                      <td>Continuous</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Primary Outcome</td>
                      <td>Depressive symptoms</td>
                      <td>PHQ-9 change score (baseline to 12 months)</td>
                      <td>Range: 0-27</td>
                      <td>Continuous</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Confounder</td>
                      <td>Age</td>
                      <td>Patient age at enrollment</td>
                      <td>Years</td>
                      <td>Continuous</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Confounder</td>
                      <td>Sex</td>
                      <td>Male or female</td>
                      <td>Self-report</td>
                      <td>Categorical</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Confounder</td>
                      <td>Race/ethnicity</td>
                      <td>Race/ethnic group</td>
                      <td>EHR demographics</td>
                      <td>Categorical</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Confounder</td>
                      <td>Baseline EASI score</td>
                      <td>Disease severity at enrollment</td>
                      <td>Range: 0-72</td>
                      <td>Continuous</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Confounder</td>
                      <td>Treatment history</td>
                      <td>Prior systemic therapies</td>
                      <td>Count</td>
                      <td>Continuous</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Confounder</td>
                      <td>Disease duration</td>
                      <td>Years since AD diagnosis</td>
                      <td>Years</td>
                      <td>Continuous</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Confounder</td>
                      <td>Insurance status</td>
                      <td>Private, Medicare/Medicaid, or other</td>
                      <td>EHR records</td>
                      <td>Categorical</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Confounder</td>
                      <td>Depression/anxiety history</td>
                      <td>Documented prior diagnosis</td>
                      <td>ICD codes</td>
                      <td>Categorical</td>
                    </tr>
                  </tbody>
                </table>
              </table-wrap>
            </fig>
          </sec>
          <sec id="mediating-moderating-and-confounding-relationships-nb-article">
            <title>2.3.5 Mediating, moderating, and confounding
      relationships</title>
            <p>These three variable roles are frequently conflated but require
      different analytic strategies. A mediator is caused by the
      exposure and carries some portion of its effect to the outcome.
      Disease activity (EASI score change), itch intensity, and sleep
      disturbance are the hypothesized mediators in this framework.
      These will not be adjusted for in the primary analysis because
      conditioning on a mediator blocks the causal pathway through which
      treatment produces its effect, biasing the estimate toward the
      null.</p>
            <p>A moderator changes the strength or direction of the
      treatment-outcome relationship and is sometimes called an effect
      modifier. Age, sex, and baseline disease severity are the
      hypothesized moderators, examined through prespecified interaction
      terms in Aim 3. A moderator does not need to be associated with
      the exposure. It only needs to change the exposure’s effect on the
      outcome.</p>
            <p>A confounder is associated with both treatment selection and
      outcomes but does not lie on the causal pathway. Confounders must
      be measured before exposure to avoid conditioning on
      post-treatment variables that could introduce bias. Insurance
      status, disease duration, treatment history, depression/anxiety
      history, and socioeconomic status are all confounders and will be
      included in the propensity score model.</p>
          </sec>
          <sec id="statistical-analysis-plan-nb-article">
            <title>2.3.6 Statistical analysis plan</title>
            <p><bold>Propensity score estimation.</bold> A propensity score is
      the probability that a patient received a particular treatment
      given their observed baseline characteristics. It compresses
      multiple confounders into a single score between zero and one and
      functions as a balancing score: patients with similar scores have,
      on average, similar distributions of observed covariates
      regardless of which treatment they received. Propensity scores
      will be estimated via logistic regression with treatment group as
      the dependent variable and the following baseline covariates as
      predictors: age, sex, race/ethnicity, baseline EASI score, number
      of prior systemic therapy failures, disease duration, insurance
      type, depression/anxiety history, and relevant comorbidities.
      Variable selection is based on subject matter knowledge of likely
      confounders. After weighting, covariate balance will be assessed
      using standardized mean differences (threshold: SMD &lt; 0.1) and
      propensity score overlap will be inspected visually to evaluate
      the positivity assumption, which requires a nonzero probability of
      receiving each treatment for every combination of covariates
      (<xref alt="Austin 2011" rid="ref-austin_introduction_2011-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Austin
      2011</xref>).</p>
            <p><bold>Primary analysis.</bold> The average treatment effect on
      the treated (ATT) will be estimated using IPTW in weighted linear
      regression models. IPTW creates a pseudo-population in which
      measured covariates are balanced across treatment groups,
      approximating what randomization would achieve. Primary outcomes
      are 12-month change scores for DLQI and PHQ-9. Point estimates
      will be reported with 95% confidence intervals, and clinical
      significance will be evaluated against established MCIDs (DLQI: 4
      points; PHQ-9: 5 points), focusing on whether confidence intervals
      exclude these thresholds and what effect sizes remain compatible
      with the data. Hypothesis testing at alpha = 0.05 will be
      reported, though a point estimate paired with its confidence
      interval is more informative for guiding treatment decisions than
      a binary significance label.</p>
            <p><bold>Effect modification analysis (Aim 3).</bold> Prespecified
      interaction terms for age, sex, and race will be included in
      regression models. Effect modification is established through the
      interaction test itself, not by comparing significance labels
      across subgroups. Stratum-specific effect sizes and confidence
      intervals will be reported to characterize the pattern of
      heterogeneity. Insurance status and socioeconomic factors will be
      examined as exploratory moderators.</p>
            <p><bold>Missing data.</bold> Missing data will be handled using
      multiple imputation by chained equations (MICE), under the
      assumption that data are missing at random conditional on observed
      covariates
      (<xref alt="White, Royston, and Wood 2011" rid="ref-white_multiple_2011-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">White,
      Royston, and Wood 2011</xref>). Because EHR data often exhibit
      missingness that is not completely at random, sensitivity analyses
      will compare imputed results to complete-case analyses.
      Substantial divergence between approaches will prompt more
      cautious interpretation.</p>
            <p><bold>Sensitivity and robustness analyses.</bold> Three
      robustness checks are planned: (1) propensity score matching (1:1
      nearest-neighbor with caliper of 0.2 standard deviations of the
      logit of the propensity score) as an alternative to weighting; (2)
      doubly robust estimation combining IPTW with outcome regression,
      which remains consistent as long as at least one of the two models
      is correctly specified; and (3) E-value calculations to quantify
      the minimum strength of association that an unmeasured confounder
      would need to have with both treatment and outcome to explain away
      observed effects
      (<xref alt="VanderWeele and Ding 2017" rid="ref-vanderweele_sensitivity_2017-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">VanderWeele
      and Ding 2017</xref>). The three assumptions underlying causal
      inference (exchangeability, positivity, and consistency) will be
      explicitly evaluated and discussed.</p>
          </sec>
          <sec id="influence-of-age-sex-and-race-nb-article">
            <title>2.3.7 Influence of age, sex, and race</title>
            <p>Demographic characteristics are likely to shape both treatment
      patterns and outcomes. Older versus younger adults may have
      different baseline quality of life and depressive symptom
      profiles, and age-related variation in insurance coverage and
      formulary restrictions may affect the probability of receiving
      dupilumab. Sex differences may emerge in how patients perceive and
      report quality of life and mood symptoms over follow-up. Race may
      relate to disparities in treatment access, with differences in
      insurance coverage, referral patterns, and prior authorization
      requirements creating selection effects in who receives biologic
      versus conventional therapy
      (<xref alt="Tackett et al. 2020" rid="ref-tackett_structural_2020-nb-article" ref-type="bibr">Tackett
      et al. 2020</xref>). All three variables will enter the propensity
      score model as covariates, and interaction analyses (Aim 3) will
      evaluate whether treatment effects differ across demographic
      subgroups. Stratum-specific results will be interpreted through
      effect sizes and confidence intervals rather than significance
      labels alone.</p>
          </sec>
          <sec id="potential-challenges-and-solutions-nb-article">
            <title>2.3.8 Potential challenges and solutions</title>
            <fig id="tbl-challenges-nb-article">
              <caption>
                <p>Table 2: Potential challenges and proposed
        solutions</p>
              </caption>
              <table-wrap>
                <table>
                  <colgroup>
                    <col width="38%"/>
                    <col width="62%"/>
                  </colgroup>
                  <thead>
                    <tr>
                      <th>Challenge</th>
                      <th>Proposed Solution</th>
                    </tr>
                  </thead>
                  <tbody>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Confounding by indication: dupilumab patients have
                more severe, refractory disease</td>
                      <td>IPTW with thorough covariate balance assessment (SMD
                &lt; 0.1); doubly robust estimation as sensitivity
                analysis; E-value calculations for unmeasured
                confounding</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Missing PRO data from incomplete follow-up or
                inconsistent EHR documentation</td>
                      <td>Multiple imputation by chained equations with
                sensitivity analyses comparing complete-case results;
                evaluation of whether missingness patterns relate to
                patient characteristics or outcome risk</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Selection bias from differential out-of-pocket costs
                affecting who receives dupilumab</td>
                      <td>Include insurance status and socioeconomic
                indicators in propensity score model; assess residual
                imbalance post-weighting</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Treatment switching or discontinuation during
                follow-up</td>
                      <td>Intention-to-treat analysis as primary approach;
                per-protocol analysis as sensitivity check with
                documented switching rates and reasons</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Insufficient sample size for subgroup analyses by
                race</td>
                      <td>Report stratum-specific estimates with confidence
                intervals; acknowledge precision limitations
                transparently; avoid interpreting nonsignificance as
                absence of effect</td>
                    </tr>
                  </tbody>
                </table>
              </table-wrap>
            </fig>
          </sec>
          <sec id="study-timeline-nb-article">
            <title>2.3.9 Study timeline</title>
            <fig id="tbl-timeline-nb-article">
              <caption>
                <p>Table 3: Study timeline</p>
              </caption>
              <table-wrap>
                <table>
                  <thead>
                    <tr>
                      <th>Activity</th>
                      <th align="center">Year 1 Q1-Q2</th>
                      <th align="center">Year 1 Q3-Q4</th>
                      <th align="center">Year 2 Q1-Q2</th>
                      <th align="center">Year 2 Q3-Q4</th>
                    </tr>
                  </thead>
                  <tbody>
                    <tr>
                      <td>IRB approval and data access agreements</td>
                      <td align="center">✓</td>
                      <td align="center"/>
                      <td align="center"/>
                      <td align="center"/>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Cohort identification and data extraction</td>
                      <td align="center">✓</td>
                      <td align="center">✓</td>
                      <td align="center"/>
                      <td align="center"/>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Propensity score estimation and balance
                assessment</td>
                      <td align="center"/>
                      <td align="center">✓</td>
                      <td align="center"/>
                      <td align="center"/>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Primary analyses (Aims 1 and 2)</td>
                      <td align="center"/>
                      <td align="center">✓</td>
                      <td align="center">✓</td>
                      <td align="center"/>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Effect modification analyses (Aim 3)</td>
                      <td align="center"/>
                      <td align="center"/>
                      <td align="center">✓</td>
                      <td align="center"/>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Sensitivity analyses and robustness checks</td>
                      <td align="center"/>
                      <td align="center"/>
                      <td align="center">✓</td>
                      <td align="center"/>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                      <td>Manuscript preparation and dissemination</td>
                      <td align="center"/>
                      <td align="center"/>
                      <td align="center">✓</td>
                      <td align="center">✓</td>
                    </tr>
                  </tbody>
                </table>
              </table-wrap>
            </fig>
            <p/>
          </sec>
        </sec>
      </sec>
    </body>
    <back>
      <ref-list>
        <title>3. References</title>
        <ref id="ref-afshari_unraveling_2024-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Afshari</surname>
                <given-names>Moeina</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Kolackova</surname>
                <given-names>Martina</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Rosecka</surname>
                <given-names>Michaela</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Čelakovská</surname>
                <given-names>Jarmila</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Krejsek</surname>
                <given-names>Jan</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Unraveling the skin; a comprehensive review of atopic dermatitis, current understanding, and approaches</article-title>
            <source>Front Immunol</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2024">2024</year>
            <volume>15</volume>
            <issn>1664-3224</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2024.1361005</pub-id>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38500882</pub-id>
            <fpage>1361005</fpage>
            <lpage/>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-austin_introduction_2011-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Austin</surname>
                <given-names>Peter C.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>An Introduction to Propensity Score Methods for Reducing the Effects of Confounding in Observational Studies</article-title>
            <source>Multivariate Behav Res</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2011-05">2011</year>
            <month>05</month>
            <volume>46</volume>
            <issue>3</issue>
            <issn>1532-7906</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/00273171.2011.568786</pub-id>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21818162</pub-id>
            <fpage>399</fpage>
            <lpage>424</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-chopra_assessing_2018-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Chopra</surname>
                <given-names>Rishi</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Silverberg</surname>
                <given-names>Jonathan I.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Assessing the severity of atopic dermatitis in clinical trials and practice</article-title>
            <source>Clin Dermatol</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2018">2018</year>
            <volume>36</volume>
            <issue>5</issue>
            <issn>1879-1131</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.clindermatol.2018.05.012</pub-id>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30217273</pub-id>
            <fpage>606</fpage>
            <lpage>615</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-drucker_burden_2017-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Drucker</surname>
                <given-names>Aaron M.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Wang</surname>
                <given-names>Annie R.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Li</surname>
                <given-names>Wen-Qing</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Sevetson</surname>
                <given-names>Erika</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Block</surname>
                <given-names>Julie K.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Qureshi</surname>
                <given-names>Abrar A.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>The Burden of Atopic Dermatitis: Summary of a Report for the National Eczema Association</article-title>
            <source>J Invest Dermatol</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2017-01">2017</year>
            <month>01</month>
            <volume>137</volume>
            <issue>1</issue>
            <issn>1523-1747</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jid.2016.07.012</pub-id>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27616422</pub-id>
            <fpage>26</fpage>
            <lpage>30</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-eckert_impact_2017-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Eckert</surname>
                <given-names>Laurent</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Gupta</surname>
                <given-names>Shaloo</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Amand</surname>
                <given-names>Caroline</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Gadkari</surname>
                <given-names>Abhijit</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Mahajan</surname>
                <given-names>Puneet</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Gelfand</surname>
                <given-names>Joel M.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Impact of atopic dermatitis on health-related quality of life and productivity in adults in the United States: An analysis using the National Health and Wellness Survey</article-title>
            <source>J Am Acad Dermatol</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2017-08">2017</year>
            <month>08</month>
            <volume>77</volume>
            <issue>2</issue>
            <issn>1097-6787</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2017.04.019</pub-id>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28606711</pub-id>
            <fpage>274</fpage>
            <lpage>279.e3</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-finlay_dermatology_1994-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Finlay</surname>
                <given-names>A. Y.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Khan</surname>
                <given-names>G. K.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI)–a simple practical measure for routine clinical use</article-title>
            <source>Clin Exp Dermatol</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="1994-05">1994</year>
            <month>05</month>
            <volume>19</volume>
            <issue>3</issue>
            <issn>0307-6938</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2230.1994.tb01167.x</pub-id>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8033378</pub-id>
            <fpage>210</fpage>
            <lpage>216</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-kroenke_phq-9_2001-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Kroenke</surname>
                <given-names>Kurt</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Spitzer</surname>
                <given-names>Robert L.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Williams</surname>
                <given-names>Janet B. W.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>The PHQ-9</article-title>
            <source>J GEN INTERN MED</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2001-09">2001</year>
            <month>09</month>
            <date-in-citation content-type="access-date">
              <year iso-8601-date="2026-04-15">2026</year>
              <month>04</month>
              <day>15</day>
            </date-in-citation>
            <volume>16</volume>
            <issue>9</issue>
            <issn>1525-1497</issn>
            <uri>https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1525-1497.2001.016009606.x</uri>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1046/j.1525-1497.2001.016009606.x</pub-id>
            <fpage>606</fpage>
            <lpage>613</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-eichenfield_guidelines_2014-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Eichenfield</surname>
                <given-names>Lawrence F.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Tom</surname>
                <given-names>Wynnis L.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Berger</surname>
                <given-names>Timothy G.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Krol</surname>
                <given-names>Alfons</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Paller</surname>
                <given-names>Amy S.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Schwarzenberger</surname>
                <given-names>Kathryn</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Bergman</surname>
                <given-names>James N.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Chamlin</surname>
                <given-names>Sarah L.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Cohen</surname>
                <given-names>David E.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Cooper</surname>
                <given-names>Kevin D.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Cordoro</surname>
                <given-names>Kelly M.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Davis</surname>
                <given-names>Dawn M.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Feldman</surname>
                <given-names>Steven R.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Hanifin</surname>
                <given-names>Jon M.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Margolis</surname>
                <given-names>David J.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Silverman</surname>
                <given-names>Robert A.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Simpson</surname>
                <given-names>Eric L.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Williams</surname>
                <given-names>Hywel C.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Elmets</surname>
                <given-names>Craig A.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Block</surname>
                <given-names>Julie</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Harrod</surname>
                <given-names>Christopher G.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Smith Begolka</surname>
                <given-names>Wendy</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Sidbury</surname>
                <given-names>Robert</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Guidelines of care for the management of atopic dermatitis: Section 2. Management and treatment of atopic dermatitis with topical therapies</article-title>
            <source>J Am Acad Dermatol</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2014-07">2014</year>
            <month>07</month>
            <volume>71</volume>
            <issue>1</issue>
            <issn>1097-6787</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2014.03.023</pub-id>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24813302</pub-id>
            <fpage>116</fpage>
            <lpage>132</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-silverberg_adult_2013-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Silverberg</surname>
                <given-names>Jonathan I.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Hanifin</surname>
                <given-names>Jon M.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Adult eczema prevalence and associations with asthma and other health and demographic factors: A US population-based study</article-title>
            <source>J Allergy Clin Immunol</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2013-11">2013</year>
            <month>11</month>
            <volume>132</volume>
            <issue>5</issue>
            <issn>1097-6825</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2013.08.031</pub-id>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24094544</pub-id>
            <fpage>1132</fpage>
            <lpage>1138</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-silverberg_patient_2018-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Silverberg</surname>
                <given-names>Jonathan I.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Gelfand</surname>
                <given-names>Joel M.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Margolis</surname>
                <given-names>David J.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Boguniewicz</surname>
                <given-names>Mark</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Fonacier</surname>
                <given-names>Luz</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Grayson</surname>
                <given-names>Mitchell H.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Simpson</surname>
                <given-names>Eric L.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Ong</surname>
                <given-names>Peck Y.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Chiesa Fuxench</surname>
                <given-names>Zelma C.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Patient burden and quality of life in atopic dermatitis in US adults: A population-based cross-sectional study</article-title>
            <source>Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2018-09">2018</year>
            <month>09</month>
            <volume>121</volume>
            <issue>3</issue>
            <issn>1534-4436</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.anai.2018.07.006</pub-id>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30025911</pub-id>
            <fpage>340</fpage>
            <lpage>347</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-simpson_two_2016-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Simpson</surname>
                <given-names>Eric L.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Bieber</surname>
                <given-names>Thomas</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Guttman-Yassky</surname>
                <given-names>Emma</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Beck</surname>
                <given-names>Lisa A.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Blauvelt</surname>
                <given-names>Andrew</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Cork</surname>
                <given-names>Michael J.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Silverberg</surname>
                <given-names>Jonathan I.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Deleuran</surname>
                <given-names>Mette</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Kataoka</surname>
                <given-names>Yoko</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Lacour</surname>
                <given-names>Jean-Philippe</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Kingo</surname>
                <given-names>Külli</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Worm</surname>
                <given-names>Margitta</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Poulin</surname>
                <given-names>Yves</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Wollenberg</surname>
                <given-names>Andreas</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Soo</surname>
                <given-names>Yuhwen</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Graham</surname>
                <given-names>Neil M. H.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Pirozzi</surname>
                <given-names>Gianluca</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Akinlade</surname>
                <given-names>Bolanle</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Staudinger</surname>
                <given-names>Heribert</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Mastey</surname>
                <given-names>Vera</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Eckert</surname>
                <given-names>Laurent</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Gadkari</surname>
                <given-names>Abhijit</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Stahl</surname>
                <given-names>Neil</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Yancopoulos</surname>
                <given-names>George D.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Ardeleanu</surname>
                <given-names>Marius</given-names>
              </name>
              <string-name>SOLO 1 and SOLO 2 Investigators</string-name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Two Phase 3 Trials of Dupilumab versus Placebo in Atopic Dermatitis</article-title>
            <source>N Engl J Med</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2016-12">2016</year>
            <month>12</month>
            <volume>375</volume>
            <issue>24</issue>
            <issn>1533-4406</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1610020</pub-id>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27690741</pub-id>
            <fpage>2335</fpage>
            <lpage>2348</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-tackett_structural_2020-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Tackett</surname>
                <given-names>Kelly Jo</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Jenkins</surname>
                <given-names>Frances</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Morrell</surname>
                <given-names>Dean S.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>McShane</surname>
                <given-names>Diana B.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Burkhart</surname>
                <given-names>Craig N.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Structural racism and its influence on the severity of atopic dermatitis in African American children</article-title>
            <source>Pediatr Dermatol</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2020-01">2020</year>
            <month>01</month>
            <volume>37</volume>
            <issue>1</issue>
            <issn>1525-1470</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/pde.14058</pub-id>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31854003</pub-id>
            <fpage>142</fpage>
            <lpage>146</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-vanderweele_sensitivity_2017-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>VanderWeele</surname>
                <given-names>Tyler J.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Ding</surname>
                <given-names>Peng</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Sensitivity Analysis in Observational Research: Introducing the E-Value</article-title>
            <source>Ann Intern Med</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2017-08">2017</year>
            <month>08</month>
            <volume>167</volume>
            <issue>4</issue>
            <issn>1539-3704</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7326/M16-2607</pub-id>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28693043</pub-id>
            <fpage>268</fpage>
            <lpage>274</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-yu_systematic_2018-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Yu</surname>
                <given-names>Sherry H.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Drucker</surname>
                <given-names>Aaron M.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Lebwohl</surname>
                <given-names>Mark</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Silverberg</surname>
                <given-names>Jonathan I.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>A systematic review of the safety and efficacy of systemic corticosteroids in atopic dermatitis</article-title>
            <source>J Am Acad Dermatol</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2018-04">2018</year>
            <month>04</month>
            <volume>78</volume>
            <issue>4</issue>
            <issn>1097-6787</issn>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2017.09.074</pub-id>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29032119</pub-id>
            <fpage>733</fpage>
            <lpage>740.e11</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-basra_determining_2015-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>Basra</surname>
                <given-names>M. K. A.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Salek</surname>
                <given-names>M. S.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Camilleri</surname>
                <given-names>L.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Sturkey</surname>
                <given-names>R.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Finlay</surname>
                <given-names>A. Y.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Determining the minimal clinically important difference and responsiveness of the Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI): Further data</article-title>
            <source>Dermatology</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2015">2015</year>
            <volume>230</volume>
            <issue>1</issue>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1159/000365390</pub-id>
            <fpage>27</fpage>
            <lpage>33</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
        <ref id="ref-white_multiple_2011-nb-article">
          <element-citation publication-type="article-journal">
            <person-group person-group-type="author">
              <name>
                <surname>White</surname>
                <given-names>Ian R.</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Royston</surname>
                <given-names>Patrick</given-names>
              </name>
              <name>
                <surname>Wood</surname>
                <given-names>Angela M.</given-names>
              </name>
            </person-group>
            <article-title>Multiple imputation using chained equations: Issues and guidance for practice</article-title>
            <source>Stat Med</source>
            <year iso-8601-date="2011">2011</year>
            <volume>30</volume>
            <issue>4</issue>
            <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/sim.4067</pub-id>
            <fpage>377</fpage>
            <lpage>399</lpage>
          </element-citation>
        </ref>
      </ref-list>
    </back>
  </sub-article>
</article>
